<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> <channel><title>curl | bash</title><description>Mkdox curlpipebash by pforret</description><link>https://curlpipebash.com/</link><atom:link href="https://curlpipebash.com/feed_rss_updated.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><language>en</language> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:16:25 -0000</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:16:25 -0000</lastBuildDate> <ttl>1440</ttl> <generator>MkDocs RSS plugin - v1.17.1</generator> <image> <url>None</url> <title>curl | bash</title><link>https://curlpipebash.com/</link> </image> <item> <title>frankenphp.dev/install.sh</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;The FrankenPHP installer is a 154-line POSIX shell script that installs the FrankenPHP application server — a modern PHP app server built on Caddy — via &lt;code&gt;curl -sL https://frankenphp.dev/install.sh | bash&lt;/code&gt;. It takes three different installation paths depending on what it finds: on Linux with dnf, it adds an RPM repository from &lt;code&gt;rpm.henderkes.com&lt;/code&gt; and installs a native package with systemd integration; on Linux with apt, it does the equivalent via a DEB repository at &lt;code&gt;deb.henderkes.com&lt;/code&gt;; and on all other systems (macOS, or Linux without apt/dnf), it downloads a static binary from GitHub releases directly into the current directory. The script uses &lt;code&gt;tput&lt;/code&gt; for terminal formatting instead of raw ANSI codes, and on Linux it applies &lt;code&gt;setcap cap_net_bind_service&lt;/code&gt; to let the binary bind ports 80/443 without root.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://curlpipebash.com/blog/2026/01/frankenphpdevinstallsh/</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://curlpipebash.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">curl | bash</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://curlpipebash.com/blog/2026/01/frankenphpdevinstallsh/</guid> </item> <item> <title>get.docker.com</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;The Docker convenience install script at &lt;code&gt;get.docker.com&lt;/code&gt; is a substantial 764-line shell script that configures Docker&#39;s official package repositories and installs Docker Engine, CLI, containerd, Compose, Buildx, rootless extras, and (as of v28.2) the Docker Model plugin on Linux systems via &lt;code&gt;curl -fsSL https://get.docker.com | bash&lt;/code&gt;. It supports Debian/Ubuntu/Raspbian (apt), CentOS/Fedora/RHEL (dnf/yum), handles architecture detection, version pinning, channel selection (stable/test), and China mirror support (Aliyun, Azure). The entire script body is wrapped in a &lt;code&gt;do_install()&lt;/code&gt; function as protection against partial downloads during pipe execution — a classic defensive pattern. Roughly 150 lines are comments, including a 97-line header that doubles as thorough usage documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://curlpipebash.com/blog/2026/01/getdockercom/</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://curlpipebash.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">curl | bash</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://curlpipebash.com/blog/2026/01/getdockercom/</guid> </item> <item> <title>laravel.build/example-app</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;laravel.build&lt;/code&gt; installer is a compact 52-line script generated server-side by Laravel&#39;s build service, invoked via &lt;code&gt;curl -sL https://laravel.build/example-app | bash&lt;/code&gt;. The URL path (&lt;code&gt;example-app&lt;/code&gt;) determines the project name, and query parameters can customize which services are included. The script requires Docker to be running, pulls the &lt;code&gt;laravelsail/php84-composer:latest&lt;/code&gt; image, runs &lt;code&gt;laravel new&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sail:install&lt;/code&gt; inside a container, then uses Laravel Sail to pull and build Docker images for mysql, redis, meilisearch, mailpit, and selenium. No software is installed on the host beyond the project directory — everything runs in Docker. Notably, the script has no shebang line and supports &lt;code&gt;doas&lt;/code&gt; as a sudo alternative alongside the usual &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://curlpipebash.com/blog/2026/01/laravelbuildexample-app/</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://curlpipebash.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">curl | bash</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://curlpipebash.com/blog/2026/01/laravelbuildexample-app/</guid> </item> <item> <title>php.new/install/mac</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;php.new&lt;/code&gt; macOS installer is a compact 212-line script that sets up a ready-to-go PHP development environment via &lt;code&gt;curl -sL https://php.new/install/mac | bash&lt;/code&gt;. It downloads pre-built binaries for PHP 8.5, Composer, and the Laravel installer from &lt;code&gt;download.herdphp.com&lt;/code&gt; — the infrastructure behind Laravel Herd — and drops them into &lt;code&gt;~/.config/herd-lite/bin/&lt;/code&gt;. It also fetches the Mozilla CA certificate bundle from &lt;code&gt;curl.se&lt;/code&gt;, creates a minimal &lt;code&gt;php.ini&lt;/code&gt;, wires &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;PHP_INI_SCAN_DIR&lt;/code&gt; into your shell profile, and generates its own uninstall script. The whole thing is essentially &#34;Herd Lite&#34;: a standalone subset of Laravel Herd that skips the GUI and gives you three executables and a config directory.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://curlpipebash.com/blog/2026/01/phpnewinstallmac/</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://curlpipebash.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">curl | bash</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://curlpipebash.com/blog/2026/01/phpnewinstallmac/</guid> </item> <item> <title>raw.githubusercontent.com/basherpm/basher/master/install.sh</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;The basher installer is a minimal 61-line bash script that installs &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/basherpm/basher&#34;&gt;basher&lt;/a&gt;, a package manager for shell scripts, via &lt;code&gt;curl -sL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/basherpm/basher/master/install.sh | bash&lt;/code&gt;. It git-clones the basher repository into &lt;code&gt;~/.basher&lt;/code&gt; and appends initialization lines to the user&#39;s shell profile. Zero boilerplate — no colors, no banners, no spinners. Every line appended to the shell profile is tagged with the marker &lt;code&gt;##basher5ea843&lt;/code&gt;, making it trivial to grep and remove them on uninstall. The script supports bash, zsh, sh, and fish, with fish getting its own 5-line initialization block.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://curlpipebash.com/blog/2026/01/rawgithubusercontentcombasherpmbashermasterinstallsh/</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://curlpipebash.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">curl | bash</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://curlpipebash.com/blog/2026/01/rawgithubusercontentcombasherpmbashermasterinstallsh/</guid> </item> </channel></rss>